Umesh B. Gajbhiye

Mobile: 9421671668

E-mail: umesh.gajbhiye5565@gmail.com

Career Objective

To make a significant impact through my marketing prowess and functional skill set on a business unit, in an environment where I can contribute to the professional and personal success of those around me while continuously improving my skills and abilities. To use my communication and negotiation skills to full fill both the customer's demands and the organization's targets.

Key Skills & Competencies

- Experienced in planning marketing campaigns, getting collaterals developed and promoting the products and services through online and print media.
- I have a proven ability to build new business relationships and new territories, and experience in developing business opportunities within existing client bases.
- Ability to impact sales through coaching, counseling, and influencing others to accomplish desired outcomes.
- o Researching, developing and executing new product launches.
- o Identifying and selling against merchandising plans.
- Compiling and maintaining a customer database that documents appropriate customer information and contacts.
- o Preparing call reports and monthly business reports with sufficient detail and in a timely manner.
- Marketing Concepts, Positioning, People Management, Sales Planning, Competitive Analysis,
 Understanding the Customer, Product Development Self Development, Communication, Interpersonal and
 Problem Solving Skills. High level of confidence and determination. Adoptability to different environments
 and quick learning capabilities.
- o Team Work, Flexible, Punctual and Interest to Learn New Things.

Currently Working

Kohinoor Technical Institute Branch Manager

Research local market conditions, Identify current and prospective sales and expansion opportunities, Develop forecasts, financial objectives and business plans, Meet business goals and metrics. Direct all operational aspects such as distribution operations, customer service, human resources, administration, marketing and sales. Bring out the best of branch's personnel by providing training, coaching, development and motivation. Locate areas for improvement, Propose corrective actions .Share knowledge and insights with other branches and headquarters. Manage budget and allocate resources appropriately. Address customer and employee satisfaction issues promptly. Adhere to high ethical standards. Comply with all regulations/applicable laws. Prepare and present reports on market movement and penetration

Work History

AK Group Pvt. Ltd

Regional Manager 5th August 2018 to March 2022

- Collaborating with senior executives to establish and execute a sales goal for the region.
- Managing a sales team in order to maximize sales revenue and meet or exceed corporate-set goals, Forecasting annual, quarterly and monthly sales goals.
- Assisting sales personnel in their techniques.
- Developing specific plans to ensure growth both long and short-term.
- Educating sales team with presentations of strategies, seminars and regular meetings.
- Reviewing regional expenses and recommending improvements.

Achievers Law India

Sr. Field Office 16th Nov 2016 to 30th June2018

Keep the current procedures updated and when needed adjust or implement new ones. Provide correct flowcharts and keep procedures very efficient within the legal possibilities of ISO, are able to make detailed procedures together with the responsible head of department or manager in the required area. Maintain the quality page on share point always updated with the latest procedures, safety, sheets, flowcharts, addendums etc. Ensure reports are made within a timeline and reported to the TQP Manager. Assist with audits when needed and set up internal audits in an efficient way.

Behave ethically: understand ethical behavior and business practices and ensure it is consistent with standards and aligned with the values of the company

Vakrangee Software Ltd.

As an ADC (Asst. District Coordinator) 12/10/2011 to 20/11/2013.

Responsibilities: Developing mini banks branches in rural areas

Participating in district sales events as well as regional and national distributor trade shows. Facilitate in set up of PC centers in the blocks (Panchayat Coordinators means mini bank of nationalized bank). Supervise respective FI activities under the assigned blocks. Ensure timely sign off from block nodal officer of the respective banks Facilitate Identify the market of financial inclusive services (microfinance, remittance, account opening, insurance etc) in consultation with PC. Coordinate and train PC for smooth delivery of financial services saving account, insurance, loan, remittance etc. Audits of various PC under the block to check the status & its operations escalate any functional / operational issue to respective block coordinator. Provide the communication and advertisement materials to PC.

Cyber Peripherals Pvt.Ltd. & Lenovo India pvt.ltd.

FOS Team Leader (11-03-2009 to 15-8-2011.)

Providing highly professional sales and marketing expertise and back up to sales representatives. To ensure that the Sales Team is working at its optimum level

To ensure that target sales are being met

Responsibilities:

- Developed, implemented, monitored and reviewed all marketing strategies for the business on both a regional and national basis.
- Continuously improved the marketing processes within the business through the development of a structured marketing plan, segmentation analysis along with optimizing client data to ensure cost effective marketing programmers were delivered.
- Responsible for developing the product strategy for two new web hosting brands and a new website provider brand
- Managed a busy and focused team of more than 10 sales, marketing & product professionals including PR, junior assistants and online marketing specialists.

Education:

Master of Business Administration (MBA)

With specialization in Marketing Management under Dr. Babasaheb Ambedkar Marathawada University Aurangabad passed in June 2011.

Bachelor of Business Administration (BBA)

Dr. Babasaheb Ambedkar Marathawada University. Aurangabad, University in 2007.

Project Reports:

BBA PROJECT

"Personnel Management" in Nirlep Pvt. Ltd, in 2007.

DFS PROJECT

"Comparative Study of Two Wheelers Companies" in 2008.

MBA INPLANT PROJECT

"Retail & Distribution Channel of Lenovo India pvt.ltd." in 2010.

MBA FINAL PROJECT

"Promotional Tools of Advertising for Lenovo India pvt.ltd." in 2011

Skills

• MS-Word /Excel and Internet Application.

• Certificate Course : Diploma in Information Technology and (MS-CIT)

• Languages : C, C++, VB,

• DBMS / RDBMS : Ms Access

Extra-Curricular Activities

- Completed Housing.com training for 9 days in the month of March 2014 in Mumbai.
- Completed T.C.S. training for 3weeks in the month of Feb. 2011 in Aurangabad.
- Member of Organization Committee for organizing culture events in collage.
- Winner for TATVA 2010. At Dr. Babasaheb Ambedkar Marathawada University. Aurangabad.
- Actively participated in, Management skits, Role-play's and Seminar Presentations.
- Co-ordinate national event of MANAGEALIZATION held in the month of March 2011.

Personal Details:

Name	Umesh Bhimrao Gajbhiye
Date of Birth	24 th May 1985
Gender	Male
Marital Status	Married
Nationality	Indian
Passport No	P0776251
Address	Plot no.05, Navyug Colony,
	Bhawsingpura, Aurangabad.431001
State	Maharashtra
City	Aurangabad
Languages Known	English, Hindi, Marathi.
Strength	Hardworking, Sincere, Persistence and
	Punctual at Working

Declaration

I hereby declare that the above particulars are true and correct to the best of my knowledge and belief and in the event of any information being found false or incorrect, my candidature will be liable to be canceled.

Date: / / 2023

Umesh B. Gajbhiye